Finding Aid for the Henry Miller Papers LSC.0110
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Manuscripts, 1896-1980; 33 boxes, 4.5 oversized boxes (18.5 linear ft.)
  - Literary manuscripts by Miller, 1896-1978; 22 boxes, 4.5 oversized boxes (13 linear ft.)
    - "Answers to questionnaire for Playboy", undated; 1 items. (Box 82, Folder 13)
      Typescript, annotated in blue ink and signed by Miller.
    - "Apocryphe hebdomaire, parisien avec sang et feu!", 1930; 1 items. (Box 82, Folder 14)
      Typescript, 11 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - "Auctioneer", undated; 1 items. (Box 82, Folder 15)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, 4 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - "Are we going anywhere?", 1963; 2 items. (Box 82, Folder 17)
      Assorted drafts, one typescript and one typescript with holograph notes. Published in "Art Forum," 2.1 (July 1963).
    - "Bezeque, inc.", 1932; 1 items. (Box 82, Folder 18)
      Typescript, 8 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - "Bibliography of Henry Miller's works in chronological order", 1955-1958; 6 items. (Box 82, Folder 19)
      Assorted typescripts drafts. Published as an appendix in "My Friend Henry Miller" by Alfred Perlès, 1955. Folder also includes a photocopy of a revised version of the original bibliography, two copies of additions added in 1958, and a list of Miller's pub[lications].
    - Big Sur and the Oranges of Hieronymus Bosch. "Jaime de Angulo", circa 1955; 8 items. (Box 82, Folder 20)
      Two typescripts, 4 leaves each. Material is unfinished and was never used. Also includes 1 page holograph notes on Angulo, correspondence between Miller and Nancy de Angulo, Angulo's daughter, and information sent to Miller by the UCLA library.
    - Big Sur and the Oranges of Hieronymus Bosch. "This is my answer", undated; 1 items. (Box 85, Folder 1)
      Signed typescript, in manila folder with water-color illustration on front.
    - Big Sur and the Oranges of Hieronymus Bosch. "This is my answer", 1946; 1 items. (Box 85, Folder 2)
      Signed typescript with holograph corrections, boxed in a red linen case. Originally intended as a pamphlet, this work appears in modified form as the epilogue in Miller's Big Sur and the Oranges of Hieronymus Bosch (New York: New Directions, 1957).
    - Big Sur and the Oranges of Hieronymus Bosch. [Unused sections], undated; 5 items. (Box 85, Folder 3)
      Five typescripts, one with holograph corrections.
    - "Biographical note", 1938 August 15; 1 items. (Box 85, Folder 4)
      Carbon typescript with holograph notes, 8 leaves. A biographical essay based on Miller's letter to Henri Fluchere of 23 July 1938. Available on negative microfilm no. 07115.
    - "Bistre and pigeon dung", 1930; 1 items. (Box 85, Folder 5)
      Typescript, 9 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - Black Spring. "Black Spring: color-form", undated; 1 items. (Box 85, Folder 6)
      Typescript, 9 leaves. In this typescript, Miller refers to color and architecture (form) in his work "Black Spring."
    - Black Spring. "First drafts", 1932-1933; 1 items. (Box 85, Folder 7)
      Bound typescript with holograph corrections. Two watercolors are bound into the volume following the title page.
    - Black Spring. Fragments, undated; 1 items. (Box 85, Folder 8)
      Incomplete carbon typescript with irregular pagination. Available on negative microfilm no. 07115.
    - Black Spring. "Jabberwhorl cronstadt", 1933; 1 items. (Box 85, Folder 9)
      "Cronstadt: For Part II," typescript, 20 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - Black Spring. "Plans for Black Spring" [Photocopy], 1932-1933; 4 items. (Box 85, Folder 10)
      Original plans were withdrawn 6 August 1975. These 12 slides and 3 photocopies are available for reference.
    - Black Spring. "A Saturday afternoon", 1937; 1 items. (Box 85, Folder 11)
      Carbon typescript with holograph corrections. Inscribed "Copy for Emil" on first page in blue ink. Available on negative microfilm no. 07115.
    - Black Spring. "The tailor shop" and misc. typescripts, 1933; 1 items. (Box 85, Folder 12)
      Assorted typescripts. Titles include: "The tailor shop," "Scheme and significance," and "Troacadero notes." From Emil Schnellock's papers.
    - "Blaise Cendrars: salute from afar", undated; 1 items. (Box 86, Folder 1)
      Typescript. inscribed in pencil, "Written for the Lausarme Gazette, I think. H. M."
    - The Books in My Life. Appendix., undated; 2 items. (Box 86, Folder 2)
      Includes "List of books read," typescript, ca. 80 leaves and "List of books yet to be read," typescript, 11 leaves.
    - The Books in My Life. Correspondence from various persons regarding the work, 1950-1951; 1 items. (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - The Books in My Life. Misc. notes and lists, undated; 1 items. (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - The Books in My Life. Misc. typescripts, circa 1950; 2 items. (Box 86, Folder 5)
      Assorted typescripts. Includes third draft of the preface. Folder also includes 9 pages holograph notes. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - The Books in My Life. Photocopies of cards from the Library of Congress' card catalog, undated; 1 items. (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - The Books in My Life. "Preface", 1951; 1 items. (Box 86, Folder 7)
      Typescript, 15 leaves. Includes one page fragment from an unidentified source.
    - The Books in My Life. Revised typescript, circa 1950; 1 items. (Box 86, Folder 8)
      Typescript, ca. 400 leaves. Originally entitled, "The World of Books."
    - The Books in My Life. Typescript, circa 1950; 1 items. (Box 89, Folder 1)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, ca. 400 leaves. Includes first, second, and third drafts of the preface.
    - "Borderline", 1964; 2 items. (Box 89, Folder 2)
      Two typescripts, 6 leaves each, one with holograph corrections. Published in "Borderline," 1.1 (May 1964). Inscribed in blue ink, "For [Sydney] Omarr."
    - "The Bowery", undated; 1 items. (Box 89, Folder 3)
      Carbon typescript, unpublished.
    - "Brassaï", undated; 2 items. (Box 89, Folder 4)
      Carbon typescript and mimeograph, both 3 leaves. Part of an essay on Brassaï, p. 20-22 only. Includes carbon copy.
    - "Brochure." Volume 1. Bound typescript, circa 1933; 1 items. (Box 89, Folder 5)
      Notes with extensive holograph corrections. Contains excerpts from the writings of Joyce, Proust, Lawrence, Nietzsche, Spengler, Rank and Jung; excerpts from critical works; and Miller's commentary.
    - "Brochure." Volume 2. Bound typescript, circa 1933; 1 items. (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - "Brochure: the writers notes", 1932-1933; 1 items. (Box 89, Folder 7)
      Holograph notes in ink. Includes "intimate notes on June [Mansfield]." From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - "Le cadavre vivant", circa 1931-1933; 1 items. (Box 89, Folder 8)
      Typescript, 8 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers. Essay regarding a film version of "Le Cadavre Vivant" by Leon Tolstoï [Leo Tolstoy] and the cinema in general.
    - "The censor censured", circa 1958; 1 items. (Box 89, Folder 9)
      Typescript, 6 leaves. Published in "Sex and Censorship," 1.1 (1958): 4-5.
    - "Charles Candles: the moral moron", circa 1933; 1 items. (Box 89, Folder 10)
      Typescript. 19 leaves.
    - "Cinema", 1933; 1 items. (Box 89, Folder 11)
      Typescript, 27 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - The Colossus of Maroussi. "Boogie-woogie passacaglia", undated; 1 items. (Box 89, Folder 12)
      Typescript, 10 leaves. Inscribed "For Hilaire Hiler," October 28, 1941.
    - The Cosmological Eye. "An autobiographical note", undated; 1 items. (Box 92, Folder 1)
      Mimeograph, 4 leaves.
    - The Cosmological Eye. "The Brooklyn Bridge", undated; 1 items. (Box 92, Folder 2)
      Carbon typescript.
    - Cosmological Eye. "Frieden! Wie wunderbar! [Peace! It's wonderful." [German translation], undated; 1 items. (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Crazy Cock. Corrected carbon, undated; 1 items. (Box 92, Folder 4)
      Bound typescript, ca. 212 leaves.
    - Crazy Cock. Original version, undated; 1 items. (Box 92, Folder 5)
      Bound typescript, ca. 272 leaves.
    - Crazy Cock. Second version, undated; 1 items. (Box 92, Folder 6)
      Bound typescript, ca.467 leaves.
    - "Dan Harris, or the pursuit of the Minotaur", undated; 1 items. (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - "Degringolade, tintamarro, salmongondis, chinoiserio", 1930; 1 items. (Box 92, Folder 8)
      Typescript, 5 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - "Dream section", circa 1932-1934; 5 items. (Box 93, Folder 1)
      Typescript, ca. 90 leaves. Also includes assorted typescript notes on Miller's own dreams. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - "The Durrell of the Black Book days", 1959 February 9; 3 items. (Box 93, Folder 2)
      Typescripts with holograph annotations. First published in Two Cities, no. 1, April 15 1995.
    - Early manuscripts written by Miller and signed June E. Mansfield, 1925; 6 items. (Box 93, Folder 3)
      Assorted typescripts. Titles includes "Haridas the Pamphleteer," "Flute Player," "Prometheus Bound," "Auctioneer," "A Fast Fading Profession," and "His Story." Includes a note by Miller explaining the authorship of the pieces.
    - Early manuscripts, undated; 2 items. (Box 93, Folder 4)
      Two typescripts, 1 leaf each. Titles include: "Dance hall" and "The fire bird." One is signed June E. Mansfield. From the Emil Schnellock papers.
    - Echolalia. Page proofs, circa 1945; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 5)
      Published by Bern Porter, 1945.
    - [Excerpts from works by D. H. Lawrence.], 1939; 3 items. (Box 93, Folder 6)
      Typescripts. Excerpts taken from Apocalypse, Lawrence's introduction to "Magnus' memoirs of the foreign legion," and "The crown." From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - [Excerpts from the works of various authors], 1932; 3 items. (Box 93, Folder 7)
      Typescripts. Excerpts from "Challenge to Defeat" by W.H. Hale, "La Nuit Kurde," by Jean-Richard Bloch, and "Journal de Salavin" by George Duhamel. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - "Extract from a handbook written especially for Lawrence Durrell", undated; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 8)
      Typescript. 3 leaves. Discussing, in part, Jean Giono. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - "A few prefatory words about the work of Milt Figen", 1968; 2 items. (Box 93, Folder 9)
      Typescripts with holograph annotations.
    - "First Sunday in Paris", 1930; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - "For Mr. Jin: a few words for the art gallery", 1968 March; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 11)
      Typescript written for an exhibition of Miller's paintings.
    - "For Mr. Jin: a few words on the coming exhibition for Yomiuri", undated; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 12)
      Typescript, 2 leaves.
    - "For the [Jakob Gimpel] Emperor Concerto album cover", undated; 2 items. (Box 93, Folder 13)
      Carbon typescripts with holograph corrections.
    - "For Playgirl", undated; 2 items. (Box 93, Folder 14)
      Holograph manuscript, 6 leaves and typescript draft with holograph additions inserted throughout, 8 leaves.
    - "Four astrologic divisions of life", circa 1934; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 15)
      Typescript, 3 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - "Freedom, is it French?", undated; 5 items. (Box 93, Folder 16)
    - "Fuck away, fuck away!", undated; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 17)
      Holograph poem, 1 leaf.
    - "The genesis of a masterpiece", 1933; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 18)
      Carbon typescript, 7 leaves. Inscribed "to my friend, Emil Schnellock who taught me all I will ever know about painting" and "For [Robert Galen] Osborn." Available on negative microfilm no. 07115.
    - "George Grosz -- an appreciation", 1934; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 19)
      Typescript, 3 leaves.
    - Gliding into the Everglades. Correspondence, 1976-1978; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 20)
    - Gliding into the Everglades. Galleys, 1976; 3 items. (Box 93, Folder 21)
      Three sets of galleys, one incomplete and one with holograph corrections.
    - Gliding into the Everglades. Misc. layouts, cover art, and photos, circa 1976; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 22)
      Includes photo of Henry Miller used for the book
    - Gliding Into the Everglades. "The mystery of the Japanese woman", undated; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 23)
      Typescript, 4 leaves.
    - Gliding into the Everglades. Page proofs, 1976; 2 items. (Box 93, Folder 24)
      Two sets of page proofs corrected and approved by Miller and Robert Durand. Published in 1977 by the Lost Pleiades Press.
    - Gliding into the Everglades. Typescript (photocopy), 1976; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 25)
    - "God, Nijinsky and the stock exchange", circa 1939; 3 items. (Box 93, Folder 26)
      Unpublished typescripts.
    - Greece. "For the Greek book (Anne Poor)", 1963; 12 items. (Box 93, Folder 27)
      Three typescripts, one with holograph corrections. Includes 7 letters from Anne Poor to Henry Miller regarding the project and 1 page notes from Edith Hamilton's "The Greek Way." Published by Viking Press, 1964.
    - Hazot Va-Hezi [Half-Past Midnight]. "Preface", 1956 July 1; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 28)
      Carbon typescript of the preface for the Hebrew edition of Half Past Midnight (illustrated by Bezalel Schatz, translation by Aharon Amir, 'Zohar' editions, Tel-Aviv).
    - Hamlet. "Apropos of "Bastard Death'." [Letter from Miller to Fraenkel, June 19, 1936], 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 29)
      This version published in "New England Weekly" prior to publication of "Hamlet." Typescript. 7 leaves. From the Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - Hamlet. "Dybbuk or death and bastard death", undated; 1 items. (Box 93, Folder 30)
      Typescript, 14 leaves.
    - Hamlet [Correspondence between Miller, Perlès, and Fraenkel concerning Hamlet], 1935; 7 items. (Box 94, Folder 1)
      Carbon typescripts, 47 leaves.
    - Henry Miller Miscellanea drafts (1 of 2), circa 1945; 2 items. (Box 94, Folder 2)
      Assorted typescripts with extensive corrections by Miller, Bern Porter and with printer's markings. Selections published by Bern Porter, Berkeley, 1945.
    - Henry Miller Miscellanea drafts ( 2 of 2), circa 1945; 4 items. (Box 94, Folder 3)
      Assorted typescripts. Titles include "Cirque medrano," "Epilogue to Black Spring," "To the reader of this excerpt titled 'Once I passed through...'" and a work schedule. Selections published by Bern Porter, Berkeley, 1945.
    - Henry Miller Miscellanea. Galley proofs and page proofs, 1945; 5 items. (Box 94, Folder 4)
      Proofs with holograph annotations. Published by Bern Porter, Berkeley, 1945.
    - Henry Miller Miscellanea. Layouts, sample pages, correspondence, costs and estimates, 1944-1945; ca. 20 items. (Box 94, Folder 5)
      Layouts for cuts, sample pages, notes in pencil on printing costs and estimates, and correspondence between Bern Porter and Jack Stauffacher concerning printing and publication.
    - "Homage to the Maestro [Jakob Gimpel]", 1970 June 30; 2 items. (Box 94, Folder 6)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, and one carbon copy.
    - "If I am neither asleep nor awake...", 1973 October 1; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 7)
      Holograph poem, on Miller's letterhead.
    - "The immortal bard", 1962; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 8)
      Three typescripts with holograph corrections, 5 leaves each. Published in "review of English Literature," IV (January 1963).
    - "Impressions of Bruges", 1953; 2 items. (Box 94, Folder 9)
      2 typescripts, 5 leaves each.
    - Insomnia: or, The Devil at Large. "Preface." Japanese edition, undated; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 10)
      Holograph on yellow lined paper, initialed by the author. Inscription: "For special ed. of Insomnia Japanese ed. This one not used."
    - "The intellectual tailor's son", undated; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 11)
      Holograph manuscript in small notebook, 9 x 14 cm.
    - "The intellectual tailor's son." Photocopy, undated; 6 items. (Box 94, Folder 12)
      Photocopy of holograph notebook.
    - Interview of Henry Miller by George Wickes, 1961; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 13)
      Conducted in London on 12 September 1961. Typescript with holograph corrections in blue ink, 60 leaves. Audio version of this interview available in the Audio/Visual Materials series of this collection.
    - Interview of Henry Miller by George Wickes. Another draft, 1961; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 14)
      Conducted in London on 12 September 1961. Typescript with holograph corrections in blue ink, 36 leaves. Audio version of this interview available in the Audio/Visual Materials series.
    - "Is fiction?", undated; 3 items. (Box 94, Folder 15)
      3 typescripts, 3 leaves each.
    - Joseph Delteil: Essays in Tribute. "Joseph Delteil", 1962; 2 items. (Box 94, Folder 16)
      Typescript with extensive holograph corrections, first draft, 5 leaves and another typescript draft, 5 leaves.
    - "Joseph Delteil and François d'Assise", 1960; 3 items. (Box 94, Folder 17)
      Three typescripts. Published in "Two Cities," (May 15, 1960).
    - "Last Will and Testament." Addenda, undated; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 18)
      Typescript with holograph notes, 4 leaves. From Emil Schnellock Papers. Written "after seeing 'Cock of the Air.'"
    - "Lawrence", undated; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 19)
      Five leaves of holograph notes on D. H. Lawrence. Removed from Miller's copy of John Middleton Murry's Son of Woman (London: Jonathan Cape Ltd., 1931).
    - "Letter from Egypt via Washington, D. C.", undated; 2 items. (Box 94, Folder 20)
      Typescript and carbon copy. Copy of a letter dated April 1, 1924, Washington, D.C. Printed as a "Booster" insert for v. 2, no. 8.
    - "Letter to Cherie", 1932; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 21)
      Typescript, 7 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - "Letter to my dear friends", 1929; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 22)
      Typescript, 4 leaves. Letter regarding Marcel Proust. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - "Letter to the park commissioner." Holograph manuscript, 1927; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 23)
      Holograph manuscript, 10 leaves. Signed Albert E. Higginson [pseudonym].
    - "Letter to the park commissioner." Typescript, 1936; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 24)
      Typescript, 10 leaves. Signed Aloysius T. Higginbotham, Jr. [pseudonym].
    - "Letter to Rona", undated; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 25)
      Typescript, 5 leaves.
    - "Letter to Swasey--May 25", undated; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 26)
      Incomplete typescript, 2 leaves.
    - List of works by and about Henry Miller, 1964-1965; 6 items. (Box 94, Folder 27)
      Typewritten list of articles about Henry Miller, published works, works contracted but not published, and collectors of Henry Miller's watercolor paintings. Includes 2 letters of transmittal from Henry Miller to Brooke Whiting.
    - "Love and how it gets that way", 1961; 3 items. (Box 94, Folder 28)
      Typescript, 26 leaves. Note on title page reads: "written expressly for Miriam Cendrars." Also includes two copies of the piece as published in the German paper.
    - "La manie de l'aquarelle", undated; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 29)
      Typescript, 16 leaves. Published in "Synthèses," X (February 1956).
    - "La marche au soleil", circa 1933; 1 items. (Box 94, Folder 30)
    - Max and the White Phagocytes. "An open letter to Surrealist everywhere", 1937-1938; 3 items. (Box 96, Folder 1)
      Two typescript versions. Original version entitled "An Open Letter to Herbert Read and the English Surrealists, to Andre Breton and his French cohorts, to the Dutch, Belgian, Swedish, Swiss, American, African, Japanese and Chinese Surrealists scattered ..."
    - Max and the White Phagocytes. "Reflection on 'Extase'", circa 1936; 4 items. (Box 96, Folder 2)
      Mimeographed manuscript and correspondence about release of the film. Includes letters from Jacques Koerpel and Samuel Cummins of Eureka Productions to Miller and a copy of a newspaper article regarding the film "Extasy."
    - Max and the White Phagocytes. "Scenario", circa 1936; 1 items. (Box 96, Folder 3)
      Typescript, 9 leaves. Included in a letter to Hilaire Hiler dated September 14, 1936.
    - "Message to Lilik Schatz over Israeli radio", undated; 1 items. (Box 96, Folder 4)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, 4 leaves.
    - Mezzotints, 1925; 4 items. (Box 96, Folder 5)
      Typescripts. Four in a series of 15 prose poems copied from originals in Emil Schnellock's collection. Signed "June E. Mansfield," but work is attributed to Henry Miller.
    - [Miller's first book of penmanship], circa 1896; 2 items. (Box 96, Folder 6)
      Partially completed book of penmanship. Accompanying note from Miller regarding the book and the elementary school were it was begun.
    - Miscellaneous excerpts from the works of various authors, undated; 18 items. (Box 96, Folder 7)
      Typescripts. Selected by Henry Miller, with a few annotations by him.
    - Miscellaneous fragments, circa 1932; 4 items. (Box 96, Folder 8)
      Assorted typescripts. Includes fragments from Crazy Cock, and unidentified fragment regarding obscenity, and a typescript entitled "Copy for Wilke."
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts, undated; 1 items. (Box 96, Folder 9)
      Bound carbon typescript with holograph annotations and irregular pagination. Item is composed of separate essays, reviews of movies and books, letters, and material for newspaper columns.
    - Miscellaneous materials, undated; 1 items. (Box 96, Folder 10)
      Includes typescript copies of newspaper articles, and notes on and excerpts from the work of other authors.
    - Miscellaneous notes and lists, undated; 1 items. (Box 96, Folder 11)
    - Moloch, undated; 1 items. (Box 96, Folder 12)
      Bound carbon typescript, 383 leaves. Inscription: "Unpublished novel - the first!"
    - Money and How it Gets That Way. Typescript, undated; 1 items. (Box 97, Folder 1)
      Incomplete typescript. 14 leaves. From the Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - Money and How it Gets That Way. Typescripts, proofs, and correspondence, 1945; 7 items. (Box 97, Folder 2)
      Galley proofs, page proofs, holograph notes and typescript of foreword to 2nd edition. Includes four letters between Bern Porter and George Van Vechten, Jr. pertaining to publication.
    - "Montparnasse goes South for the crisis", circa 1932; 3 items. (Box 97, Folder 3)
      Two typescript drafts. From Emil Schnellock's Papers. Also, another typescript, given by Miller to Hilair Hiler.
    - "More about the fabulous concubine of Dr. Chang", 1957; 1 items. (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Murder the Murderer. Page proofs and galley proofs, 1945; 2 items. (Box 97, Folder 5)
      Includes instructions to the printer. Published by Bern Porter, Berkeley, 1945. Also appeared in Remember to Remember (New York: New Directions, 1947).
    - Murder the Murderer, 1945; 3 items. (Box 97, Folder 6)
      Typescript with holograph corrections and annotations by Bern Porter. Includes Parts 1 ("Open letter to Private Alfred Perlès") and 2 ("Murder the murderer"). Correspondence from various persons to Bern Porter pertaining to sale and legality of the pamphlets.
    - "My life with Sevasty", undated; 3 items. (Box 97, Folder 7)
      Unpublished typescript of original draft with holograph notes at end, plus typescript in carbon. Watercolor illustration originally included; missing as of September 1984.
    - "The new instinctavism", undated; 1 items. (Box 97, Folder 8)
      Incomplete typescript by Miller and Alfred Perlès. See microfilm copy of "Paris notebook" in box 128 of this collection for complete manuscript.
    - Nexus. Fragments cut for obscenity, undated; 1 items. (Box 97, Folder 9)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, 23 leaves (p. 259-281).
    - Nexus. Pages cut from Nexus, undated; 1 items. (Box 97, Folder 10)
      Typescript, 24 leaves (p. 259-281).
    - The Nightmare Notebook, 1940-1941; 1 items. (Box 97, Folder 11)